prospect.org 2011-10-07

# Privacy Policy

_The American Prospect_ , Inc. (collectively referred to in this Privacy Statement as "we," "us," or " _The American Prospect_ , Inc.") recognize the importance of protecting the privacy of all information provided by users of our websites, subscribers to our magazines, registrants for our events, recipients of our e-mail newsletters, donors, and all of our customers. We created this policy with a fundamental respect for our users' right to privacy and to guide our relationships with our users. This privacy statement discloses the privacy practices for all products and services owned by _The American Prospect_ , Inc. 

**INFORMATION COLLECTION AND USE**

_The American Prospect_ , Inc. collects information from our website users, magazine subscribers, donors and customers. In this section of our privacy policy, we will describe the type of information we collect and how we use it to provide better services to our customers. 

**Registration and Ordering**  
When using some of our websites and signing up for certain selected services (such as ordering a subscription), users must first register. During registration, users are required to give their contact information (such as name, e-mail address, mailing address and Zip code). We also may wish to collect demographic information (such as hobbies, purchasing habits, and areas of interest). For internal purposes, we use this information to communicate with users and provide requested services, and, for our website visitors, to provide a more personalized experience on our sites. We use aggregate demographic information about our audience to improve our service, for marketing purposes and/or industry reporting purposes.   
Many of our products and services are free to subscribers who meet certain demographic criteria. Examples include web articles and blog posts. Independent auditors may need to certify the eligibility of these subscribers. In order to do that, we may collect unique identifiers (such as mother's maiden name) that we disclose to the auditors strictly for industry reporting and audit verification purposes.   
For our services that require payment (such as certain events, donations and subscriptions), we also collect credit card information (such as account name, number, expiration date, and verification code), which is used for billing purposes only, and is not otherwise shared. 

**E-mail Newsletters**  
If users wish to subscribe to our e-mail newsletters, we ask for contact information (such as name, e-mail address and, occasionally, demographic information). We use this information in the same manner as we use contact information in the registration and ordering process described above. Recipients of our newsletters can unsubscribe using the instructions listed at the end of the e-mail newsletter. 

**Surveys and Contests**  
From time to time we invite users to provide information via surveys. Participation in these surveys are completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether to disclose requested contact information (such as name and mailing address) and demographic information (such as Zip code or hobby). In addition to other uses set forth in this policy, contact information collected in connection with surveys and to monitor or improve the use and satisfaction of the site. 

**Interactive Features**  
At some of our sites, we offer interactive and community features such as discussion boards. Note that all personal information sent or posted via such features becomes public information for which we are not responsible. 

**E-mail This Article**  
If users elect to use our referral service for informing a friend about our articles, sites and services, we may ask them for the friend's name and e-mail address. _The American Prospect_ , Inc. will store and use this information to send the friend an invitation. This information may also be used to provide information about our company and related products and services. The friend may contact us as specified in the subsequent message to request that no further communications be sent. 

**Communications with Us**  
We have features where users can submit information to us (such as our comment/feedback forms). Letters to the editor and similar submissions may be made public. Requests for service, support or information may be forwarded as needed to best respond to a specific request. We may retain e-mails and other information sent to us for our internal administrative purposes, and to help us to serve customers better. 

**Communications from Us: Service Updates, Special Offers**  
In order to best serve our customers, we may send updates that contain important information about our sites and services. For example, we may send new members a welcome message, confirmations on purchases or verification of password and username for our password-protected sites. We may also communicate with a user to provide requested services and for account-related issues via e-mail, phone or regular mail.   
We offer our users the option to receive information about our company and related services. Users can choose not to receive these communications, as set forth in our Permission section below. 

**Automatic Data Collection**  
Our websites have features that automatically collect information from users, to deliver content specific to users' interests and to honor their preferences. This information assists us in creating sites that will serve the needs of our users.   
We use "cookies," a piece of data stored on the user's hard drive containing information about the user. Cookies benefit the user by requiring login only once, thereby saving time while on our site. If users reject the cookies, they may be limited in the use of some areas of our site. For example, the user may not be able to participate in sweepstakes, contests or drawings. Additionally, we may note some of the pages the user visits on our site through the use of pixel tags (also called clear gifs). The use of cookies and pixels enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our sites.   
Some of our business affiliates use cookies on our sites in ads or promotions. However, we have no access to or control over these business affiliates' cookies; we urge users to read their privacy policies for information.   
For our internal purposes, we gather date, time, browser type, navigation history and IP address of all visitors to our site. This information does not contain anything that can identify users personally. We use this information for our internal security audit log, trend analysis and system administration, and to gather broad demographic information about our user base for aggregate use.   
We may combine demographic information supplied by a subscriber at registration with site usage data to provide general profiles, in an aggregate non-personally identifiable form, about our users and their preferences in the content of the site and advertising. We may share this composite information with our advertisers and business affiliates to help them better understand our services.   
We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. Some of these companies, such as Google use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. 

**WITH WHOM YOUR INFORMATION IS SHARED**

When we have co-branded, customized, private label, powered by or sponsored products and services, or when we join with other parties to provide specific services, we may share (provide and receive) personal information with them. We do not share credit card information with such third parties.   
On occasion, we may provide targeted lists of names and offline and online contact information for marketing purposes to third parties, subject to our Permission policies. We give users the option of not having their name or contact information disclosed to third parties, as set forth in the Permission section. Other than as set forth above, we do not share personally identifiable information with other companies, apart from those acting as our agents in providing our product(s)/service(s), and which agree to use it only for that purpose and to keep the information secure and confidential. Also, our parent, subsidiary and affiliate companies, entities into which our company may be merged, or entities to which any of our assets, products, sites or operations may be transferred, will be able to use personal information. We will also disclose information we maintain when required to do so by law, for example, in response to a court order or a subpoena or other legal obligation, in response to a law enforcement agency's request, or in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) our rights or property. Users should also be aware that courts of equity, such as U.S. Bankruptcy Courts, might have the authority under certain circumstances to permit personal information to be shared or transferred to third parties without permission.   
We may share aggregate information, which is not personally identifiable, with others. This information may include usage and demographic data, but it will not include personal information. 

Member agrees that during the term of this Agreement, the Member Site will have a privacy policy that (i) clearly and conspicuously notifies visitors to the Member Site that such site uses a third party to collect information on the sites, including through the use of cookies and web beacons; and (ii) where reasonable or practicable will provide a direct link to Nielsen Online's Privacy Policy with the following (or similar) language: "Click [here](http://www.nielsen-netratings.com/privacy/sitecensus.htm) to learn more information about how we use a third party service to collect and use information on this Web site".

**CORRECTING/UPDATING PERSONAL INFORMATION**  
If a user's personally identifiable information changes (such as Zip code), we provide a way to correct or update that user's personal data. The user should contact [rboriskin@prospect.org](mailto:rboriskin@prospect.org). 

**PERMISSION**  
Our users are given the opportunity to choose whether to receive information not directly related to the registered services from our affiliates and us. Users also have the opportunity to choose whether to have personal information shared with third parties for marketing purposes. Instructions for how to exercise this choice are contained in e-mails sent by us, on our websites and in each of our publications. Please note that we will endeavor to implement requests within a reasonable time, although for a time users may continue to receive mailings, etc., transmitted based on information released prior to the implementation of the request. Users will continue to receive information directly related to their registered services, so they always are kept informed. 

**SECURITY**  
We use reasonable precautions to protect our users' personal information and to store it securely. Sensitive information that is transmitted to us online (such as a credit card number) is 128-bit encrypted and is transmitted to us securely. In addition, access to all of our users' information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted. Only employees who need the information (for example, a billing clerk or a customer service representative) to perform a specific job are granted access to personally identifiable information. Finally, the servers on which we store personally identifiable information are kept in a secure environment. 

**PURCHASING RESTRICTIONS**  
_The American Prospect_ , Inc. does not sell subscriptions for purchase by children. If you are under 18, you may use our website only with the involvement of a parent or guardian. 

**SAFE SHOPPING GUARANTEE**  
Under the Fair Credit Billing Act, a credit card issuer cannot make you liable for charges in excess of $50.00 that result from the unauthorized use of your credit card. There are similar federal laws that relate to debit cards. Exceptions do apply, and you will have to comply with rules of your credit card or debit card issuer, so please contact your card issuer for further details.   
If through no fault of your own, a credit card or debit card issuer assesses you a fee because of the unauthorized use of your credit card or debit card on our site, _The American Prospect_ , Inc. will reimburse you for such amount up to $50.00. Please contact rboriskin@prospect.org for details. 

**LINKS**  
Our websites contain links to other sites. _The American Prospect_ , Inc. is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each website to which we may link that may collect personally identifiable information. 

**NOTIFICATION and CHANGES**  
If we change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so our users are aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under which circumstances, if any, we disclose it. Users should check this policy frequently to keep abreast of any changes. 

For questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site or any dealings with _The American Prospect_ , Inc, contact us at:   
Business Manager  
_The American Prospect_ , Inc.   
1710 Rhode Island Ave. NW  
12th Floor  
Washington, DC 20036  
202-776-0730
